Never forget why you are the church.
This morning, we continue into week 2 of our series upon this rock.
We are going over each of our core values one by one.
The reason why it's called upon this rock is when Jesus asked his
disciples, who are people saying that I am, they said
things like Jeremiah and Elijah and John the
Baptist, and those were great names, but that's not who Jesus is.
Amen.
And so we asked another level of question, hey, who
do you say that I am?
And Peter answered, you are the son of God.
You are the Messiah, the one who, the promised
one, the anointed one.
In other words, you are the Christ.
And listen, that's exactly who he is.
We have to know who Jesus is to worship him for
who he is.
And so he then says, upon this rock, right?
He changes, he says, Peter, your name will be changed to rock, and we
see that that means a little rock that can be moved, and then he said, but upon this
rock, a rock that is foundational.
That is the proclamation that Jesus is Lord upon this rock.
He will build his church.
And so what we've done here in this series is very simple.
We are building upon the rock.
The chief cornerstone of Jesus, and we're
doing so in core values, the things that we come
together in agreeance on.
Again, remember, if we're going to accomplish and see our
vision come to fruition, we must do so by living out the mission.
And we will not live out this mission unless we value the
right things in life.
You're going to hear our vision and mission statements over and over again.
We have a tendency to reject redundancy.
I remember when I used to lead worship for years and years
and years, and we had the multi tracks, and we were able
to have 4 new songs every single week, and I loved it.
We sang new songs every week and people was like, listen, we love
these songs and we fall in love with them and then you don't sing them again, ever, ever, ever.
We do new songs every Sunday.
There's a reason why we have regular songs that we sing because
that's how we learn things.
We learn things by repetitiveness.
Well, listen, in order to put something to our heart, we must be consistent in it.
Culture built is culture repeated.
Words do matter.
Statements do matter.
What we declare by mouth will be lived out in action, if
we keep it in our hearts.
So our vision at Cedar Grove is very simple.
Cedar Grove Baptist Church exists to create a space where
people and families can meet Jesus, find community and
grow in their faith.
We want to get we want to see this happen with our mission, our purpose
is to love others unconditionally.
Learn about God increasingly, live the share Jesus intentionally,
and lead others to Christ continually in Lebanon, Tennessee,
and throughout the whole world.
We do that by valuing the right things.
Last week we went over our 1st core value.
It was family.
How do we value our family?
Through our core value statement of agreement?
This is what we said.
We said, I will uphold the sanctity of the family.
Let's pray this morning.
Father, we thank you, Lord, for this morning.
We thank you for your word.
God, we thank you for this gathering.
So God, I pray that you allow me to preach with power.
God, those that have ears to hear, may they hear.
Listen, Jesus, name me pray.
And everybody said, amen.
How do we uphold the sanctity of the family?
Well, there's 3 things that we looked over.
going to quickly, very quickly review, but the 1st thing is by
making my family a priority and intentionally spending quality
time with them.
Where are you the most intentional?
Personal ambitions, personal success?
Is your time with your family simplified to yelling
at them to hurry up to the next event list?
And that's convicting to me?
Because I feel like all we do in my family is rush to the next thing
and rush to the next thing and you're late.
I don't know if anyone's ever had a 4 and 6 year old, but I don't know
why it takes 30 minutes to get out the car.
You understand what I'm saying?
I mean, I'm like the amount of times that I tell River,
River, hurry up.
And she's like a little old lady, just kind of just coming out of the car.
I can't handle it.
Right?
But sometimes we get so rushed that we miss the moments, right?
We miss the intentionality.
It happens to all of us.
Matthew 6, verse 19 through 21, lay not up for yourselves
treasures upon earth, where moth and rust do corrupt
and where thieves break through and steal, but lay up for yourselves treasures in heaven,
where neither moth nor rust does corrupt,
and where thieves do not break in, nor do they steal, for where your treasure
is, there where your heart be also.
You know what we're doing in our culture and society?
Our heart is everywhere else, and we're trying to keep up and catch up to it.
And it's not working, church.
We got to make sure that our heart is where it needs to be.
We uphold the sanctity of the family now.
I will say this.
Listen, if your family comes before Christ, you have made your family into an idol.
And people say all the time, well, Jacob, my family is the most important thing in my life.
Well, then your family's an idol.
Jesus is the most important thing.
Listen, I cannot love my wife unless I love Jesus more than her.
I cannot love my kids unless I love Jesus more than them.
You understand what I'm saying?
Sometimes we get it so mixed up.
So by making my family a priority and intentionally
spending quality time with them.
But also we do this by making the Bible the primary source of instruction.
Listen, this is not a new truth.
When God gave Moses the law.
It was not to limit the people, but to protect the people.
In Deuteronomy chapter 6, verse 6 through 7.
It says this, and these words, which I command thee this day, shall
be in your heart and shall teach them diligently
unto thy children.
You shall teach them diligently unto thy children and shalt take of them when
you sittest in the house.
And when thou walkest by the way, and when thou liest down, and when
you riseest up, listen, we are all learning from someone
or something, especially our children.
I think it's Shane Pruitt who has said a few times
on social media is, he's one of the leading youth
preachers really in the country right now.
If you haven't heard of Shane Pruitt, you live under a rock in this world.
But anyway, he said, listen, it used to be that we were
so big on, hey, we need to get our kids disciple.
Guess what?
That's true, but your kids are already being discipled whether you are doing it or not.
You understand what I'm saying?
Your child is a student of the world unless
you come in and make sure that you're discipling them in Christ.
So we got to be careful making the Bible the primary source of instruction.
We uphold the sanctity of the family by not only those 2 things,
but by daily praying for my family and with my family.
What a privilege it is to talk with God.
Acts 114.
These were these all with one mind were continually devoting themselves to prayer.
Billy Graham once said this about family.
No subject is closer to my heart than the family.
The moral foundation of our country is in danger of
crumbling as families break up and parents neglect their responsibilities.
You know what we've done as parents today?
We've made our responsibilities, making sure our kid can hit a baseball.
We've made sure that our kid was in the drama club.
We made sure that our kid had the latest, greatest video game.
We made sure that our kid had the nicest clothes, all these things.
We have prioritized our kids in all the wrong ways, and we're
seeing them leave the faith one by one.
in drows.
Are y'all with me this morning?
Listen, we were neglecting our responsibility.
By the way, you say, well, I don't have no kids.
Well, if you're part of this family, I know for a fact you got 40 kids because
they're all registered for Iana.
Amen?
You got a whole bunch of kids.
Listen, that's how the family, that's how the church family works.
You say, well, listen, I'm not big on
I'm not big on kids.
What you talking about?
What do you mean?
So who you pour into then?
You know, the Bible says that the that the older women should
pour into the younger women, the older men should pour into the younger men.
You know what we do?
Usually we look down upon them.
Oh, look at how they at.
Look at how they do.
Well, then show them what the Bible says about it.
Are y'all with me?
I'm about to preach a whole nother message.
But Mary, keep our families holy.
Amen.
And listen, I stand before you, a man.
Understand that I'm living in this same world you're living in?
I've got the same temptations of worldly ambitions just like you do.
I want my kids to be successful in everything, right?
Listen, River.
She has no interest in learning how to ride a bike.
That bothers me.
You understand what I'm saying?
Like, what if you try to run away?
You gonna walk?
You know what I'm saying?
No I'm kidding.
But listen, seriously, I'm like, let's go let's go learn how to ride the bike.
She said, I don't really want to.
I don't care to.
And me, I'm thinking, I've done something wrong.
But all I'm trying to say is I have those same,
those same pools in the world to do all the things the world says is right.
We have to make sure that we are intentional upholding the
sanctity of our family through God's word.
Amen?
Our next core value that we're going to talk about this morning is integrity.
Our statement of agreement is, I will live daily with
integrity in thought, word, and deed.
Now, what is integrity?
In the Old Testament, the Hebrew word translated
integrity means the condition of being without blemish,
completeness, perfection, sincerity, soundness, uprightness, wholeness.
Integrity in the New Testament means honest and adherence
to a pattern of good works.
Now, listen, we understand that we cannot live in perfect integrity because
we still have the flesh, we still struggle with sin.
We're still in our process of sanctification that will end praise
God and glorification when we're like Christ.
But we see examples of integrity all throughout scripture.
But there's only one man who was perfect in his integrity.
And his name was Jesus.
Amen?
If you remember after Jesus was baptized, the Holy Spirit directed
him to the wilderness, where he fasted for 40 days and 49s.
It was in these 40 days and 49s, the devil himself
came and tempted Jesus in his time of physical weakness.
Now, I want to say something how critical it is to understand this.
The enemy, the devil, the opposer, right, the
father of all lies, Lucifer Satan, he is not omnipresent.
You understand what I'm saying?
So sometimes this is what we say.
Oh, well, Lucifer, Satan's just on me today.
Well, well, he can't be on you.
And then on that person, then on that person, that's not how he works.
Now, he has a demonic force, right?
He has an army of fallen angels with him that can that can
terrorize and do all things.
But understand this.
The devil can only be in one place at one time.
Okay.
He chooses to go straight to Jesus here.
He knew that if he could get Jesus just to drop his integrity just for a moment.
If he could get Jesus just to give in to temptation,
just for a moment, he could ruin the whole plan of the gospel.
Y'all with me?
This is some this is some big time temptation here.
Right?
We sit here and we act like, man, I just feel like I'm Jesus in the wilderness.
No, you don't.
Stop that.
Listen, hey, we don't want that.
We got to make sure that we understand just how capable
of the enemy is, but also that we have victory over him through Jesus.
You say, how does that coincide?
It just does.
Amen?
We have victory, but we're still fighting to fight.
Okay?
So he did so 3 times trying to tempt Jesus 3 different ways.
First, when we see in Matthew chapter 4, verse 3 and 4.
If you want to turn there, you can.
Matthew chapter 4, verse 3 and 4.
to be on the screen.
And the tempter came and said to him, if you are the son of God,
command that these stones become bread.
But he answered and said, it is written, man shall not live on bread
alone, but on every word that proceeds out of the mouth of God.
See, here the devil tempted him through the lust of the flesh.
He knew Jesus was hungry, so he attacked his appetite.
You do realize Jesus was 100% fully and truly man.
He had to eat just like we had to eat.
He hurt just like we hurt.
He felt just like we felt.
He was tapped and tried just like we are yet without sin.
Okay?
Understand, that's how perfect he is in his integrity.
He's not eating for 40 days and 49.
Let me just tell you something.
Every agape feast, all right?
You know the agape feast that we do?
All right, if you don't, we're going to have one soon, okay?
Y'all can join us.
We eat before service.
Amen.
It's awesome.
We join it with the Lord's Supper.
But some of us crazy men had an idea.
And you can join in on it.
But we want to we want to be focused on why we're doing this agape
piece, why we're having this unity.
So we just say, hey, if you want to fast with us, we can.
Well, we usually do like a day.
Well, last time someone said, hey, let's do like 3 days.
Now let me tell you something.
I'm not trying to be a lack of spiritual person right here.
But 3 days without food gets you a little bit hangry, amen?
And listen, as the pastor, there was no way that I was going to come in and
eat on a 60 something hour empty stomach or whatever it is and then preach.
Listen, if you, that's called white knuckle in the pool pit.
don't want to do that as a preacher.
So what I'm trying to say is, could you imagine 40 days and 40 nights without food?
And the devil himself comes
to you to try to tempt you.
With food.
Here's the thing, church, you realize if we cannot be trusted with our appetite,
We will never be able to stand against the wilds of the devil.
Appetite, just not just include food.
Your lust has appetite for all the things that satisfies it.
The world knows where to hit us regarding our appetite, our flesh,
lust, food, anger, gossip, or all the main
ingredients in our society.
Listen, you can't drive down the street without seeing something
that hits the flesh and tries to try to get it riled up.
That's what our culture is.
Think about it for a moment.
What is one of the most viral conversations happening in our nation right now?
unless you're living under a rock.
It's the Lindsay Clancy trial.
I don't know if you know anything about it, but listen, in 2023,
this woman killed her 3 children by strangulation and is now
pleading not guilty by reason of insanity.
In other words, did she know that she was doing wrong, when she did it, that she just snapped?
Did she do this?
all these things?
Now you might say, listen, you don't sound too sympathetic.
Well, I'm not a lawyer, amen?
I'm just a preacher.
Neither is all these fanatic social media users that know
better than the people that are committed to this case.
But I do know one thing.
I do know one thing.
Exodus chapter 20, verse 13 says, you shall not murder.
It's as simple as that.
Now, listen, you say, what does this have to do with the lust of the flesh?
I'm not even going to try to get into all the details.
I just told you, we don't know the information, and I'm
not even trying to say that she didn't have something going on.
I'm just trying to say that 3 kids died.
Our society has become absolutely infatuated with this trial.
Why?
It includes everything the flesh loves.
Hear me?
It includes everything our flesh loves, murder,
anger, confusion, division, gossip,
slander.
Listen, however you feel about it.
Whichever way you look at it, what it is, it feeds
our wicked appetites.
The devil knows what he's doing.
The 2nd temptation we see the devil use is Matthew chapter
4, verse 5 through 7, then the devil took him into the holy city and
had him stand on the pinnacle of the temple.
And said to him, if you are the Son of God, throw yourself down,
for it is written, he will command his angels concerning you, and on their
hands they will bear you up so that you will not strike your foot against the stone.
Jesus said to him, on the other hand, it is written, you shall not put the Lord your God to the test.
Here he is tempting him with the pride of life.
Jesus walked in humility.
He had all the power of the universe, yet he came as a servant.
How often do we give in to the temptation to choose us
over anything and anyone else.
It's almost as if we test God by saying things like,
well, God, I deserve to be happy.
We make our decisions based on what will make us happy.
We make our decisions based on what will pump us up and fluff us up in the world.
I need you to know something.
Listen, we got to walk in humility just like Christ
walks in humility church.
We don't deserve to be happy.
We deserve hell.
There is no pride in hell, just eternal torment.
Everyone is in hell for the same reason.
They earned hell the same way.
They rejected Jesus.
So we see here that he tried to tempt him with the pride of life.
Then came the 3rd temptation, Matthew chapter 4, verse 8 through 10.
We're moving quickly here because we're going to get to our main 3 points.
Amen.
Again, the devil took him to a very high mountain and showed him all the kingdoms
of the world and their glory and said to him, all these things I will give you
if you fall down and worship me.
And Jesus said to him, go, Satan, for it is written,
you shall worship the Lord your God and serve him only.
Here we see the lust of the eyes.
How often do we worship the things that we can see in this world?
Guys, listen, it's so easy.
We get so caught up in idolatry, we don't even know that we're worshiping anymore.
If Jesus would have taken the devil up for any of these temptations,
would have lost his integrity.
He would have lost his perfection, his holiness, his without blemish state.
He would have been, by definition, blemished.
In doing so, he would have lost his, like I said, integrity, therefore
lost the ability to be the sacrifice for the sins of the world.
Now you might be thinking, This is a high standard for us.
Preacher, are you kidding me right now?
You're telling me that we need to be like Christ?
Well, yeah.
That's who we follow.
Amen.
I mean, come on now.
Listen, we're called to imitate Christ.
1st Peter one, 15 and 16 says, but like the holy one who called you,
be holy, your cells also in all your behavior, because it
is written, you shall be holy, for I am holy.
Ephesians 424 and put on the new self, which is in the likeness
of God, and has been created in righteousness and holiness of the truth.
Do we value what Christ values?
Philippians 2.5.
Let this mind be in you, which was also in Christ Jesus.
Guys, listen, we have to value integrity as God did.
We have to value integrity as Jesus did.
And there's a lot of these false doctrines that are going around this world.
And I understand that we are so allergic to
legalism, we're so allergic to wokeism.
We're so allergic to all these little isms.
I need to let you know something.
If there's any doctrine that you are trying to follow,
that takes holiness out of the equation.
You are following a false doctrine, and whoever is
teaching it to you is a false teacher.
He is a wolf in sheep clothing.
There's no other option there.
Anytime you read God's word.
What you're gonna find is, you're gonna find a draw to be
more holy as he is holy.
The Holy Spirit is going to convict you and
point out and expose the things in your life that you need to adjust towards Christ.
Y'all with me this morning?
How do we do this?
How do we wrestle with the old man, the old woman, as we fight the
temptations of the lust of the flesh, the pride of life, and the lust of the eyes?
How do we live daily with integrity in thought, word, and deed?
That's what we're going to answer this morning.
First, the 1st way we're gonna do this, together, is by meditating on things that honor God.
By meditating on things that honor God.
Jesus in the wilderness was able to stand against the devil
because his mind was set on the task at hand.
He was preparing for his earthly ministry that
would end in his death at Calvary.
He, even though he knew what was coming, his mind was right.
By the way, this is the only way to navigate our life, it is to
control our thoughts.
Has anyone ever had thoughts that got out of control?
How fast does it happen?
Like that.
Listen, as a pastor, you know what happens with me?
I just going to go ahead and tell you.
What happens is somebody says something or I hear a
comment, or I hear someone didn't like something, or I hear this,
or I hear that, or I see a face that y'all make.
You make so many faces, and it's not good faces.
Like, it's not like, yeah, preacher, brother.
It's like, ugh, I don't want to be here.
Like, it's just, it's man, okay?
But listen, one little thing can happen.
Then all of a sudden, man, that sea gets planted in my mind and my heart.
I wonder if they're mad.
I wanted they're irritated.
Did I say something?
Because I talk a lot.
Did I say something that I shouldn't have said that I make a joke that
I shouldn't have done or, man, my goodness.
And then all of a sudden, my thoughts get out of control.
I start to get angry.
Well, well, how are they special to think that if
I just don't come and shake their hand, I got a lot of people to talk to.
I'm busy, and I'm this and that.
And then all of a sudden, I get to the point of,
Well, if they leave, then who cares?
And you know what the Holy Spirit does?
Hey, Jacob, chill out.
Y'all with me?
You know what I have to do?
I have to take captive those thoughts.
Guys, listen, I am I am anxiously driven up here.
You understand what I'm saying?
The littlest thing.
I can go down a route that takes me to a place that is so dark.
that I have to get myself out of it by meditating
on the good things.
You do know that there's a lot more good than bad happening in our church.
You understand that?
Listen, you may you may just be coming and not really involved.
I just want you to know, I can assure you that God is blessing
Cedar Grove Baptist Church.
God is blessing this church family.
Listen, there's a lot of things happening in our personal lives, but
if we would just name our blessings one by one, I guarantee the list
would quadruple the bad things happening to you today.
We have to understand.
We have to take our minds and bring them our thoughts and bring
them captive.
This is the only way.
Every action is preceded by a thought,
whether good or evil.
So what do we do?
When Paul was writing to the saints in Philippi, he was doing so, to
thank them for a financial offering they gave, but also to
encourage them in their faith.
See, but the Philippian community was also experiencing internal tensions.
Leaders were divided.
Gossip was spreading.
Outside influence was pressuring them.
False teachers were luring many away from the truth.
They were smack dab in the middle of non Christian cultures, and
they were under attack spiritually.
Does that sound familiar?
That's exactly what we are today.
So what was Paul's encouragement?
Philippians 4 verse 8, finally, brethren, whatever is true,
whatever is honorable, whatever is right, whatever is pure,
whatever is lovely, whatever is of good repute,
if there's any excellence, and if anything worthy of praise,
dwell on these things.
That word dwells an awesome word if you just look at it.
It means in the Greek to calculate, to consider,
think about, to believe, refers
to the process of reasoning or calculation, or to the logical
result arrived at by such a process.
Can I tell you something?
If we dwell in these things that Paul tells us to, you
know what, we're going to end, the process will end in.
God, you are good.
Thank you for your blessing in favor.
No matter what's going, understand that literally,
in this same book that he writes, he says, whether I have or
have not, hey, listen, God gives me strength to get through it.
In other words, it's not the circumstance that dictates our thoughts.
We put our thoughts on Christ.
No matter the circumstance.
You know what God does not honor?
He doesn't honor hateful thoughts.
He doesn't honor thoughts of worry and anxiety, thoughts
of anger or wrath, thoughts of doubt and discouragement.
Church, these thoughts are gonna happen if we do not carefully meditate on the right things.
In the Bible, meditation means actively filling your mind with God's
word, pondering his truth, and quietly reciting or muttering
scripture to let it guide your daily life.
What do you meditate on?
Is your thought life full of integrity?
If we were to play your average thought on the screen for all to see,
would it cause shame or bring glory to God?
If we're going to live daily with integrity and thought, word and deed, it
must also be by honoring God with my speech.
Is it just me or is it the 2nd hardest thing to control other than my thoughts, my tongue?
It's just me.
That's comforting.
Amen.
Y'all don't struggle with the talking.
The Bible has much to say about our speech.
In the Bible across the Old Testament, New Testament.
There is a reference to our speech or tongue over 190 times.
How many times have we said things that we wish we could take back?
We speak, and we're like, ugh.
Listen, I want you to know something.
There's no integrity in that.
So how do we honor God in our speech?
Colossians 4.6, let your speech always be with grace, as those
seasoned with salt, so that you will know how to how
you should respond to each person?
That word grace means grace, good will, favor, conveys
the sense of a gift of kindness, and favor given
to a person or persons.
Salt in the ancient world was one of the utmost importance for survival.
It was used not just to season food, but also
to preserve food.
They didn't have refrigerators, like we have today, so they use salt
to preserve so they could survive.
How many friendships could be preserved if we
would just honor God with our words?
How many church conflicts would resolve if
we would just honor God with our words?
How many people could be encouraged and lift it up if we
would just honor God with our words?
But what happens is this.
We get a dishonorable thought.
That turns into a dishonorable speech.
Well, preacher, I was just mad.
And when I get mad, I say things that I don't mean and well,
you don't know what they said or did to me.
That sounds good until you measure it up on scripture.
See, the world will say, yeah, you're right.
If they did that to you, then you have a right to just tell them off.
You know what?
You're right.
If they said that to you, you responded, you
got them good.
Mm.
Look at that verse again.
Let your speech always be with grace.
as though season was salt.
Look right here.
Look, so that you will know how you should respond to each person.
Here's the truth.
Our integrity is most important when
it becomes the most difficult to keep.
I'm gonna say it again.
Our integrity is most important when it becomes the most difficult to keep.
There is no excuse.
I'm not saying what they did to you was right.
I'm not saying what they said to you was good.
But what I'm telling you is this.
God gives us a command to be
seasoned with salt so we can respond in the right way.
I can tell you this.
I've had my fair share of church conflicts.
I don't know if you know that or not.
Could write a book one day.
Just change the names.
That might get me hurt.
But anyway, some of y'all got really nervous,
'cause some of y'all might be very young.
But listen, I've been in my fair share of
church conflicts, and I never forget my first one,
my first big one.
And I was in shock.
Absolute shock.
I'm sitting here, and I'm getting talked to in a certain way.
And where I come from, where I'm cut, you know, you don't talk
to a pastor that way kind of thing.
That's just how I was raised up.
You'd have really big dudes come and escort you out.
I didn't have those big dudes.
I didn't have Buddy and Carlos here yet.
God didn't send them.
By the way, if you talk bad to me, they're going to squirt you out, okay?
But no, seriously, I'm sitting there.
And I'll never forget.
They're just,
I mean, I'm just talking.
bringing up my age over and over again.
I used to irritate the fire out of me.
Like, we don't need no 21 year old boy telling us what.
Then why'd you vote me in?
You know, I don't understand.
Very good point, Albert.
You were here when you voted me.
You helped vote me in, brother.
And look at you here.
Praise God.
He doesn't have to be escorted out, and he can stay.
But what I'm trying to say is I stood there, and all these thoughts came into my mind.
Oh, dude, I had some good ones.
Oh, man, I was about to...
I was like, I don't need this.
I'm about to let these people have it.
And so I didn't.
I just stood there.
And I held my tongue, but it was still rolling.
And then I go, and it happens again in the parking lot.
I thought this was just, like, mythology, and I try.
I didn't know what actually happened, like, parking lot stuff, you know what I'm saying?
I was like, wow.
And in my head, I said, I'm about to show you a 21 year old boy.
But instantly, the Holy Spirit, in that moment.
Instead of me thinking on all the anger and wrath and
hurt, I consider and say that I was just angry.
I was hurt.
My feelings were hurt.
I'm just gonna be honest with you.
The Holy Spirit reminded me, hey, the text that I preached just
that morning, that an overseer,
a pastor, is not a brawler.
And so instantly, I had to take my thoughts captive.
And you know what I did?
It preserved the fact where now, the same people that were there,
I can call, we can talk, everything's fine.
God worked it all out.
Why?
Because I held my tongue.
I could have said things that he would have never forgiven.
And you know what?
If any of you were there, you would have said, well, Jacob, you had every
right to, listen, that's the world's mindset.
We gotta know how we're gonna respond to each person.
Some of y'all, the moment tension comes up.
Some of us, the moment we don't get our way, some of us,
the moment we get in a situation, we're not comfortable, whatever it is,
some of us, in that moment, we lash out with our words.
And then instantly say, well, I didn't mean it.
No, yes, you did.
There's no excuse, church.
How else are we to live daily with integrity and thought, word and deed?
Well, we see here and we're almost done by honoring God with my actions.
Not just our thoughts, not just our words, but our actions, actions
are what everyone sees, but is the last step in a walk of integrity.
James 122 says, but be doers of the word and not
hearers only, deceiving yourself, if we truly allow the word of
God to shape us into being more like Christ, we will not just know it,
we will live it.
It comes down to this.
If your thoughts are sinful, your speech will be sinful,
therefore your actions will be sinful.
You may be able to hide it for a little bit, but your heart
is going to come out in how you live.
Sin will steal our wholeness and uprightness before God.
We cannot live honestly before God and others while
living recklessly in our sin.
So, We
don't want to talk about actions too much because listen, if your thoughts aren't right.
If your speech isn't right, then your actions will never be right.
So how do you live?
What does your daily walk look like?
Isn't it integrity and your thoughts and your words and your deeds?
Let me ask you, which of these three do you struggle with the most?
Personally, I struggle with thoughts and speech.
I just do.
I just be honest with you.
I struggle with, man, I like to say things.
my mind gets to where I'm thinking all these things.
And listen, what happens is that my actions become superficial.
Instead of loving people out of a godly love, I'm
more doing it out of obligation.
Listen, I don't want to ever pass through you out of obligation.
I don't want to ever love my wife out of obligation.
Although I'm obligated to love her, whether I feel it or not.
Amen?
I'm just put that out there.
I don't want to just love my kids out of obligation, although I'm called to lead
them and love them, whether I feel it or not.
What I'm trying to say is I want to love as Christ loved me.
Even when I am at my worst.
Even in my sin, Christ died for us.
Why?
Because he loves us.
So what are you gonna do about it?
Better yet, what are you going to let God do about it?
This morning, what does God have in your life?
Does God have your thoughts?
Does God have your speech?
Does God have your actions?
I taught the kids last night, the students at round, like I told them this.
part of taking ownership of your faith, is being obedient
even when people are not looking.
There is nothing worse than a Christian being something different at church than at home.
There is nothing worse than a Christian being something different at church than at work.
Listen, you know why I quit coaching?
Say why, Pastor?
Y'all really irritating me.
Goodness gracious.
Trying to have a conversation.
You know why I quit coaching?
It's been, like, 5 or 6 years?
Because it wasn't, it wasn't a good look for what I should have been in my heart.
In other words, the way I coached was not cohesive with the way I was trying to live.
You might say, well, you should just change it or fix it.
I couldn't, therefore, I just got rid of it.
Some of these people that say they're Christians, they get to a ball game.
and they cuss out the ref.
They'll cuss out a middle school kid because they thought they should do this or do that.
They'll say all these bad things, and then they'll sit in a church house
on Sunday and act like they're all close with God.
Listen, that's not possible.
It matters.
That's integrity.
Are you the same person here than you are everywhere else in your life?
It has bad eyes closed over this place.